<!DOCTYPE document [
  <!-- These are the entity sets for ISO Latin 1 characters for the XHTML -->
  <!ENTITY % HTMLlat1 PUBLIC "-//W3C//ENTITIES Latin 1 for XHTML//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml-lat1.ent">
  %HTMLlat1;
  <!-- These are the entity sets for special characters for the XHTML -->
  <!ENTITY % HTMLsymbol PUBLIC "-//W3C//ENTITIES Symbols for XHTML//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml-symbol.ent">
  %HTMLsymbol;
  <!-- These are the entity sets for symbol characters for the XHTML -->
  <!ENTITY % HTMLspecial PUBLIC "-//W3C//ENTITIES Special for XHTML//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml-special.ent">
  %HTMLspecial;
]>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Introduction</title>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<section id="intro" name="Introduction">

 			<div id="catcherTitle">JRebirth Origins</div>
			<div id="catcherContent">The small story of JRebirth project.</div>

			<!-- <macro name="toc" section="2" fromDepth="3" toDepth="5" /> -->

			<subsection name="Origins">

				<p>Just before the 2011's summer I was bored to work with some RIA toolkit that
					don't give me enought satisfaction.
				</p>

				<p>Like many people I thought that web applications were the ultimate solution
					to build quickly beautiful and sophisticated applications. Before the advent of
					JQuery's like toolkit I built mine, a
					modularized javascript framework written
					with OOP spirit. Browser compatibility stops the projects because it requires
					too much time to manage their particularities. But the biggest pitfall is the
					Javascript language that is not enough powerful to build cleanly big
					application and not enough efficient than pre-compiled ones.
				</p>

				<p>Then I was upset by the single thread used by Flash and Flex application,
					even if I really have pleasure to work with FlexBuilder with PureMVC framework.
					Making extension of Flex components was
					also sometimes pretty hard due to
					inheritance of Flash widgets (partially resolved with new spark components).
				</p>

				<p>Unfortunately I also worked several month with Silverlight (C#) provided by
					Microsoft, the language itself have some interesting feature but ecosystem is
					not as good as the Java one. The MVVM
					pattern (Model-View-ViewModel) is a fake
					that hide a MVVCVM (Model-View-ViewController-ViewModel) where VC is the
					.xaml.cs file...
				</p>

				<p>Before working with RIA, I obviously worked with Swing and SWT/JFace
					toolkit. And finally Swing was not so bad !
				</p>

				<p>It suffered from a lot drawback like graphical performance issues,
					concurrency problems and old layout and components. But it was possible to
					write nice application powered with a pleasant Look
					&amp; Feel. </p>

				<p>So JRebirth was first thought to be a rebirth of Java Swing Toolkit in
					order to create the missing Application Framework that Swing never had.
				</p>

				<p>
					I posted on the
					<a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/toulouse-jug/d3zZJXPqUhI/discussion">ToulouseJUG</a>
					mailing list a question about my Swing revival vision, and during the
					discussion I learn taht Oracle had planned to rewrite the first JavaFX entirely
					in Java (and leave the awful fxscript
					language). So I spent the summer in
					reading beta documentation and during the autumn I began to play with it ...
					and I decided to build my own Framework.
				</p>

				<p></p>

				<p>
					The name was readily found:
					<span class="highlight">JRebirth</span>
					(for
					Java Rebirth) JavaFX Application Framework
				</p>

				<p>
					Everything began on a local SVN and then was pushed on
					<a href="https://github.com/JRebirth/JRebirth">Github</a>
					on Feb 22, 2012, few
					days after my first talk about JavaFX (2).
				</p>

			</subsection>

			<subsection name="JRebirth Objectives">

				<p>The main goal of building yet another application framework is to be the
					more convenient as possible for developpers.
				</p>

				<p>The major issue when building graphical application is to create
					unresponsive memory-hungry application, while dealing with ugly code hard to
					maintain.
				</p>

				<p>
					To adress the first point JRebirth offers a way to
					<span class="highlight">manage threads</span>
					on your behalf, for the second JRebirth
					<span class="highlight">defines layers</span>
					to maintain a good Separation of
					Concern (SoC).
				</p>

				<p>
					<span class="question">Why don't manage myself my application thread
						?
					</span>
				</p>

				<p>Writing concurrent program is more complex than you can think, problems can
					occur whenever and always when you are demoing your application with your
					client.
				</p>

				<p></p>

				<p>
					<span class="question">Layers sucks !</span>
				</p>

				<p>Are you sure ? Layer is the more basic way to organize and reuse smartly
					your code. It could seem to add some overhead to it but when you are working
					with a small or big team over years, you will
					enjoy to retrieve at the same
					place the same logic. It requires to respect some rules.
				</p>

				<p>Moreover you will have the capability to customize your layer to fit your
					need by factorizing your code.
				</p>

			</subsection>
			<subsection name="JRebirth Key features">

				<p>Main features of JRebirth Application Framework are:</p>
				<ol>
					<li>Simplify Thread Management</li>
					<li>Avoid memory leak</li>
					<li>Maintain a good SoC </li>
					<li>Be the more convenient as possible for developpers</li>
					<li>Be lightweight (and modularizable)</li>
					<li>Follow OSS spirit and Java Best Practices</li>
				</ol>
			</subsection>

			<div class="bottomLinks">
				<div class="previousDocPage">
					<a href="Toc.html">TOC</a>
				</div>
				<div class="nextDocPage">
					<a href="Installation.html"> How to install JRebirth</a>
				</div>
				<div class="tocDocPage">
					<a href="Toc.html">TOC</a>
				</div>
			</div>

		</section>
	</body>
</document>